export const questionsArr1 = [
    {
     "Question No": 1,
     "Question": "Which of the following is a type of malware that disguises itself as legitimate software?",
     "Option 1": "Adware",
     "Option 2": "Trojan",
     "Option 3": "Ransomware",
     "Option 4": "Worm",
     "Correct answer": "Trojan"
    },
    {
     "Question No": 2,
     "Question": "Which of the following is a primary advantage of static code analysis in malware analysis?",
     "Option 1": "Unpackers and obfuscation techniques are easily bypassed."
    },
    {
     "Question No": 3,
     "Question": "Which of the following types of issues can static code analysis tools detect?",
     "Option 1": "Memory leaks",
     "Option 2": "Security vulnerabilities",
     "Option 3": " Coding style violations",
     "Option 4": "All of the above",
     "Correct answer": "d"
    },
    {
     "Question No": 4,
     "Question": "What is the primary purpose of using antivirus software in malware analysis?",
     "Option 1": "To identify and remove known malware signatures from the system.",
     "Option 2": "To analyze the behavior of malware samples in a controlled environment."
    },
    {
     "Question No": 5,
     "Question": "Which stage of the software development process typically involves using static code analysis tools?",
     "Option 1": "design",
     "Option 2": "testing",
     "Option 3": "Implementation",
     "Option 4": "Deployment",
     "Correct answer": "c"
    },
    {
     "Question No": 6,
     "Question": "What is the technique that can help in comparing and classifying the suspect binary?",
     "Option 2": "Inspect Exports",
     "Option 3": "DLL Analysis",
     "Option 4": "Program Disassembly",
     "Correct answer": "a"
    },
    {
     "Question No": 7,
     "Question": "In static analysis, which of the following is used to extract strings from an entire file?",
     "Option 1": "string -a file.exe",
     "Option 2": "static -s file.txt",
     "Option 3": "extract -r file",
     "Option 4": "static -a file",
     "Correct answer": "a"
    },
    {
     "Question No": 8,
     "Question": "Which of these is an antivirus program type?",
     "Option 1": "Kaspersky",
     "Option 2": "Quick heal",
     "Option 3": "Mcafee",
     "Option 4": "All of the above",
     "Correct answer": "option 4"
    },
    {
     "Question No": 9,
     "Question": "what is the primary purpose of using antivirus software in malware analysis?",
     "Option 1": "To analyze the behavior of malware samples in a controlled environment",
     "Option 2": "To identify and remove known malware signatures from the system",
     "Option 3": "To reverse engineer the code of malware samples for vulnerability analysis",
     "Option 4": "To encrypt sensitive data on the system to prevent malware attacks",
     "Correct answer": "option 2"
    },
    {
     "Question No": 10,
     "Question": "What is the name of the tool that can be used to view the exported functions of a DLL file?",
     "Option 1": "Dependency Walker",
     "Option 2": "Process Explorer",
     "Option 3": "Resource Hacker",
     "Option 4": " PE Explorer",
     "Correct answer": "Dependency Walker"
    },
    {
     "Question No": 11,
     "Question": "What is the technique of injecting a malicious DLL into a legitimate process to execute malicious code or evade detection?",
     "Option 1": "DLL hijacking",
     "Option 2": " DLL spoofing",
     "Option 3": "DLL injection",
     "Option 4": "DLL hooking",
     "Correct answer": "DLL injection"
    },
    {
     "Question No": 12,
     "Question": "what is common method used in debugging malware to trace its execution flow?",
     "Option 1": "injecting additional malicious code ",
     "Option 2": "Analyzing network traffic",
     "Option 3": "Setting breakpoints and stepping through the code ",
     "Option 4": "Running the malware in a virtual machine ",
     "Correct answer": "Setting breakpoints and stepping through the code "
    },
    {
     "Question No": 13,
     "Question": "Which debugging technique involves monitoring systems call made by the malware ?",
     "Option 1": "Dynamic analysis",
     "Option 2": "Static analysis",
     "Option 3": "Behavioral analysis",
     "Option 4": "Data flow analysis",
     "Correct answer": "Dynamic analysis"
    },
    {
     "Question No": 14,
     "Question": "What is the purpose of utilizing a disassembler in malware debugging?",
     "Option 1": "To encrypt the malware code to evade detection",
     "Option 2": "To analyze the malware behavior during runtime",
     "Option 3": "To translate machine code into human-readable assembly language",
     "Option 4": "To simulate a secure execution environment for the malware",
     "Correct answer": "To translate machine code into human-readable assembly language"
    },
    {
     "Question No": 15,
     "Question": "What is the primary function of an assembly language?",
     "Option 1": "To directly communicate with hardware",
     "Option 2": " To create high-level programs",
     "Option 3": "To design user interfaces",
     "Option 4": "To manage databases"
    },
    {
     "Question No": 16,
     "Question": "Which of the following statements about disassembling Windows API is false?",
     "Option 1": "It involves converting machine code into assembly code.",
     "Option 2": "It can reveal the internal structure and behavior of Windows functions.",
     "Option 3": "It requires physical disassembly of computer components.",
     "Option 4": "It is a common practice in software security analysis.",
     "Correct answer": "Option 2) It requires physical disassembly of computer components."
    },
    {
     "Question No": 17,
     "Question": "What is the name of the file format that contains the metadata and MSIL code of a .NET assembly?",
     "Option 1": "Portable Executable (PE)",
     "Option 2": "Common Object File Format (COFF)",
     "Option 3": "Executable and Linkable Format (ELF)",
     "Option 4": "Mach-O",
     "Correct answer": "Portable Executable (PE)"
    },
    {
     "Question No": 18,
     "Question": "Which of the following tools is commonly used for disassembling Windows API?",
     "Option 1": "IDA Pro",
     "Option 2": "Visual Studio",
     "Option 3": "Sublime Text",
     "Option 4": "Eclipse",
     "Correct answer": "Option 1) IDA Pro"
    },
    {
     "Question No": 19,
     "Question": "Which programming language is commonly used to write disassembly scripts for Windows API?",
     "Option 1": "Python",
     "Option 2": "Java",
     "Option 3": "C++",
     "Option 4": "Ruby",
     "Correct answer": "Option 1) Python"
    },
    {
     "Question No": 20,
     "Option 1": "Reverse engineering",
     "Option 2": "Debugging",
     "Option 3": "Code optimization",
     "Option 4": "Documentation",
     "Correct answer": "Option 1) Reverse Engineering"
    },
    {
     "Question No": 21,
     "Question": "What is the most common method of distributing malware?",
     "Option 1": "Social engineering",
     "Option 2": "Physical media",
     "Option 3": "Email attachments",
     "Option 4": "Website downloads",
     "Correct answer": "option 3"
    },
    {
     "Question No": 22,
     "Question": "\nWhich of the following is NOT a typical step in disassembling Windows API?\n",
     "Option 1": "Decompilation",
     "Option 2": "Analyzing assembly instructions",
     "Option 3": "Identifying function calls",
     "Option 4": "Modifying system registry",
     "Correct answer": "Option 4) Modifying system registry"
    },
    {
     "Question No": 23,
     "Question": "Which of the following statements about disassembling Windows API is true?",
     "Option 1": "It is illegal and unethical.",
     "Option 2": "It is commonly used for malware analysis.",
     "Option 3": "It can only be done with specialized hardware.",
     "Option 4": "It is primarily used for creating software documentation.",
     "Correct answer": "Option 2)  It is commonly used for malware analysis."
    },
    {
     "Question No": 24,
     "Question": "Which of the following addressing modes is not commonly found in assembly language programming?",
     "Option 1": "Register Indirect",
     "Option 2": " Immediate",
     "Option 3": "Base-Indexed",
     "Option 4": "Stack Pointer Relative",
     "Correct answer": "Option 4"
    },
    {
     "Question No": 25,
     "Question": "What is the primary function of an assembly language?",
     "Option 1": "To directly communicate with hardware",
     "Option 2": " To create high-level programs",
     "Option 3": "To design user interfaces",
     "Option 4": "To manage databases",
     "Correct answer": "Option 1"
    },
    {
     "Question No": 26,
     "Question": "Which of the following is true about assembly language instructions?",
     "Option 1": "They are written in binary code",
     "Option 2": "They are easy to understand for beginners",
     "Option 3": "They are directly executed by the CPU",
     "Option 4": "They are platform-independent",
     "Correct answer": "Option 3"
    },
    {
     "Question No": 27,
     "Question": "What is the purpose of a mnemonic in assembly language programming?",
     "Option 1": "To represent memory addresses",
     "Option 2": "To define data types",
     "Option 3": "To provide labels for branching",
     "Option 4": " To represent opcodes in a human-readable form",
     "Correct answer": "Option 4"
    },
    {
     "Question No": 28,
     "Question": "Which component translates assembly language code into machine code?",
     "Option 1": "Compiler",
     "Option 2": " Interpreter",
     "Option 3": "Assembler",
     "Option 4": "Debugger",
     "Correct answer": "Option 3"
    },
    {
     "Question No": 29,
     "Question": "What is the role of registers in assembly language programming?",
     "Option 1": "Store high-level data structures",
     "Option 2": "Execute arithmetic operations",
     "Option 3": "Manage memory allocation",
     "Option 4": "Temporarily hold data during program execution",
     "Correct answer": "Option 4"
    },
    {
     "Question No": 30,
     "Question": "Which register in x86 architecture is used as the stack pointer?",
     "Option 1": " EAX",
     "Option 2": " ESP",
     "Option 3": "EBX",
     "Option 4": " EIP",
     "Correct answer": "Option 2"
    },
    {
     "Question No": 31,
     "Question": "What is the purpose of the \"JMP\" instruction in assembly language?",
     "Option 1": "Jump to a subroutine",
     "Option 2": "Jump to a specified memory location",
     "Option 3": "Jump if zero flag is set",
     "Option 4": "Jump if carry flag is set",
     "Correct answer": "Option 2"
    },
    {
     "Question No": 32,
     "Question": "What is the primary purpose of Dynamic Link Libraries (DLLs) in the context of malware analysis?",
     "Option 1": "To enhance system performance",
     "Option 2": "To store encrypted user data",
     "Option 3": "To provide a shared set of functions for multiple applications",
     "Option 4": "To serve as a graphical user interface component",
     "Correct answer": "Option 3"
    },
    {
     "Question No": 33,
     "Question": "How can malware leverage DLLs to evade detection?",
     "Option 1": "By encrypting the entire DLL",
     "Option 2": "By using DLL side-loading techniques",
     "Option 3": "By renaming the DLL file to a common system file name",
     "Option 4": "By increasing the DLL file size",
     "Correct answer": "Option 2"
    },
    {
     "Question No": 34,
     "Question": "Which of the following is a common technique used by malware to inject code into a legitimate DLL?",
     "Option 1": "File renaming",
     "Option 2": "DLL sideloading",
     "Option 3": "Process isolation",
     "Option 4": "Code obfuscation",
     "Correct answer": "Option 2"
    },
    {
     "Question No": 35,
     "Question": "Typical defects discovered during static analysis are",
     "Option 1": "Referencing a variable with undefined value"
    },
    {
     "Question No": 36,
     "Question": "How can digital signatures on DLL files be useful in malware analysis?",
     "Option 1": "They can identify the malware family",
     "Option 2": "They ensure the DLL is not malicious",
     "Option 3": "They provide information about the DLL's version",
     "Option 4": "They are irrelevant to malware analysis",
     "Correct answer": "Option 3"
    },
    {
     "Question No": 37,
     "Question": "Which of the following techniques can be used for detecting malicious DLLs in a system?",
     "Option 1": "Signature-based detection",
     "Option 2": "DLL encryption",
     "Option 3": "DLL virtualization",
     "Option 4": "DLL compression",
     "Correct answer": "Option 1"
    },
    {
     "Question No": 38,
     "Question": "What does fingerprinting involve in static malware analysis?",
     "Option 1": "Identifying unique characteristics or signatures of the malware",
     "Option 2": "Analyzing the behavior of the malware in a controlled environment",
     "Option 3": "Decompiling the source code of the malware",
     "Option 4": "Extracting and analyzing strings present in the malware code",
     "Correct answer": "option 1"
    },
    {
     "Question No": 39,
     "Question": "Which static analysis technique involves examining the strings present in the malware code?",
     "Option 1": "String analysis",
     "Option 2": "Binary code analysis",
     "Option 3": "Fingerprint analysis",
     "Option 4": "Behavioral analysis",
     "Correct answer": "option 1"
    },
    {
     "Question No": 40,
     "Question": "Which static analysis technique involves examining the strings present in the malware code?",
     "Option 1": "Signature-based detection",
     "Option 2": "Sandboxing",
     "Option 3": " Disassembling",
     "Option 4": "String analysis",
     "Correct answer": "option 2"
    },
    {
     "Question No": 41,
     "Question": "What does the \"REP\" prefix do in x86 assembly language instructions?",
     "Option 1": "Repeats the instruction until a condition is met",
     "Option 2": "Reverses the operation of the instruction",
     "Option 3": "Represents an error in the instruction",
     "Option 4": " Reports the execution progress of the instruction",
     "Correct answer": "Option 1"
    },
    {
     "Question No": 42,
     "Question": "What is the significance of malware fingerprinting in cybersecurity?",
     "Option 1": "It helps in creating new malware variants",
     "Option 2": " It aids in identifying and categorizing malware for threat intelligence ",
     "Option 3": "It is primarily used for removing malware from infected systems",
     "Option 4": "It has no relevance in modern cybersecurity practices",
     "Correct answer": "B"
    },
    {
     "Question No": 43,
     "Question": "Typical defects discovered during static analysis are",
     "Option 1": "Referencing a variable with undefined value",
     "Option 2": "Variables declared but used nowhere",
     "Option 3": "Programming standards and syntax violation",
     "Option 4": "All of the above",
     "Correct answer": "option 4"
    },
    {
     "Question No": 44,
     "Question": "What is static analysis?",
     "Option 1": "The analysis of batch programs",
     "Option 2": "The reviewing of test plan",
     "Option 3": "The analysis of program code.",
     "Option 4": "The use of black box testing.",
     "Correct answer": "option 3"
    },
    {
     "Question No": 45,
     "Question": "What is true regarding static analysis tools?",
     "Option 1": "It compares actual and expected result",
     "Option 2": "It can detect memory leaks",
     "Option 3": "gives quality information about code without executing it",
     "Option 4": "It tell about percentage of a code coverage",
     "Correct answer": "option 3"
    },
    {
     "Question No": 46,
     "Question": "Which of the following is a primary advantage of static code analysis in malware analysis?",
     "Option 1": "Unpackers and obfuscation techniques are easily bypassed.",
     "Option 2": "Potential malicious behavior can be identified without executing the malware.",
     "Option 3": "The malware's full runtime behavior is always revealed.",
     "Option 4": "It reliably detects zero-day malware strains.",
     "Correct answer": "B"
    },
    {
     "Question No": 47,
     "Question": "A malware analyst is using a disassembler for static code analysis. What type of information are they primarily trying to obtain?",
     "Option 1": "Network traffic patterns of the malware.",
     "Option 2": "Human-readable assembly language instructions.",
     "Option 3": "File metadata and timestamps.",
     "Option 4": "Cryptographic keys embedded in the code.",
     "Correct answer": "B"
    },
    {
     "Question No": 48,
     "Question": "Which of the following techniques would likely hinder the effectiveness of static code analysis?",
     "Option 1": "Identifying imported libraries.",
     "Option 2": "Basic string analysis.",
     "Option 3": "Obfuscation and code packing.",
     "Option 4": "Analysis of the file header.",
     "Correct answer": "C"
    },
    {
     "Question No": 49,
     "Question": "What type of information can be revealed by analyzing strings within a malware sample during static code analysis?",
     "Option 1": "Memory addresses used by the malware.",
     "Option 2": "Potential command-and-control (C2) server addresses.",
     "Option 3": "The specific cryptographic algorithms used.",
     "Option 4": "The malware's ability to evade antivirus detection.",
     "Correct answer": "B"
    },
    {
     "Question No": 50,
     "Question": "Which phase of the software development lifecycle is static code analysis typically performed in?",
     "Option 1": "Design phase",
     "Option 2": "Implementation phase",
     "Option 3": "Testing phase",
     "Option 4": "Deployment phase"
    },
    {
     "Question No": 51,
     "Question": "Which of the following is NOT a benefit of static code analysis?",
     "Option 1": "Early bug detection",
     "Option 2": "Improved code maintainability",
     "Option 3": "Enhanced code performance",
     "Option 4": "Increased security"
    },
    {
     "Question No": 52,
     "Question": "Which of the following is a potential limitation of static code analysis?",
     "Option 1": "It can detect all types of runtime errors",
     "Option 2": "It may produce false positives or false negatives",
     "Option 3": "It is faster than dynamic analysis",
     "Option 4": "It doesn't require any prior knowledge of the codebase"
    },
    {
     "Question No": 53,
     "Question": "Which file formats can Wireshark capture and analyze?",
     "Option 1": "Only JPEG",
     "Option 2": "Only MP3",
     "Option 3": "Various formats including pcap and pcapng",
     "Option 4": "Only PDF",
     "Correct answer": "C"
    },
    {
     "Question No": 54,
     "Question": "What is the purpose of the Wireshark \"Follow TCP Stream\" Feature?",
     "Option 1": " To print the captured data",
     "Option 2": "To analyze only UDP traffic",
     "Option 3": "To reconstruct and display the entire conversation of a TCP session",
     "Option 4": "To filter out non-HTTP traffic",
     "Correct answer": "C"
    },
    {
     "Question No": 55,
     "Question": "In Wireshark, what does the term \"packet\" refer to?",
     "Option 1": " A unit of data at the physical layer",
     "Option 2": "A unit of data at the data link laye",
     "Option 3": "A unit of data at the network layer",
     "Option 4": "A unit of data at the transport layer",
     "Correct answer": "C"
    },
    {
     "Question No": 56,
     "Question": "Explain the difference between a capture filter and a display filter in Wireshark.",
     "Option 1": "A capture filter is used to select specific network interfaces, while a display filter is used to filter displayed packets",
     "Option 2": " A capture filter is applied after capturing packets, while a display filter is applied during packet capture",
     "Option 3": " Both capture and display filters serve the same purpose",
     "Option 4": "A capture filter is for IPv4 packets, while a display filter is for IPv6 packets",
     "Correct answer": "B"
    },
    {
     "Question No": 57,
     "Question": "What type of malware disguises itself as legitimate software but performs malicious activities in the background?",
     "Option 1": "Virus",
     "Option 2": "Ransomware",
     "Option 3": "Rootkit",
     "Option 4": "Trojan",
     "Correct answer": "A "
    },
    {
     "Question No": 58,
     "Question": "Which type of malware is specifically designed to steal sensitive information such as login credentials and financial data?",
     "Option 1": "Worm",
     "Option 2": "Rootkit",
     "Option 3": "Spyware",
     "Option 4": "Adware",
     "Correct answer": "C"
    },
    {
     "Question No": 59,
     "Question": "Which type of malware is designed to overload a system or network with excessive traffic, causing it to become slow or unavailable?",
     "Option 1": "DDoS",
     "Option 2": "Ransomware",
     "Option 3": "Worm",
     "Option 4": "Trojan",
     "Correct answer": "A"
    },
    {
     "Question No": 60,
     "Question": "Which of the following statements about malware fingerprinting is true?",
     "Option 1": "It involves executing malware on production systems",
     "Option 2": "It relies solely on dynamic analysis techniques.",
     "Option 3": "It aims to identify malware without running it.",
     "Option 4": "It is not a common practice in malware analysis",
     "Correct answer": "C"
    },
    {
     "Question No": 61,
     "Question": "What are some challenges in disassembling Windows APIs?",
     "Option 1": "API functions may be obfuscated or packed to make analysis difficult.",
     "Option 2": "Dynamic linking and import address table (IAT) redirection can complicate analysis.",
     "Option 3": "Handling anti-debugging techniques employed by malware or protected software."
    },
    {
     "Question No": 62,
     "Question": "Which technique involves observing the actions of malware while it is running?",
     "Option 1": "Static Analysis",
     "Option 2": "Dynamic Analysis",
     "Option 3": "Signature-based analysis",
     "Option 4": "Heuristic Analysis",
     "Correct answer": "B"
    },
    {
     "Question No": 63,
     "Question": "what converts programs written in assembley language into machine instructions",
     "Option 1": "Machine Compiler",
     "Option 2": "Interpreter",
     "Option 3": "Assembler",
     "Option 4": "Converter",
     "Correct answer": "c"
    },
    {
     "Question No": 64,
     "Question": "Identify the following which is not a typical assembly language register?",
     "Option 1": "AX",
     "Option 2": "EX",
     "Option 3": "BX",
     "Option 4": "CX",
     "Correct answer": "B"
    },
    {
     "Question No": 65,
     "Question": "Which of the following statements is true regarding file obfuscation?",
     "Option 1": " It makes files more vulnerable to security threats",
     "Option 2": "It primarily focuses on optimizing file performance.",
     "Option 3": " It aims to hide sensitive information within files.",
     "Option 4": "It simplifies the process of understanding file functionality.\n",
     "Correct answer": " It aims to hide sensitive information within files."
    },
    {
     "Question No": 66,
     "Question": "What is the purpose of file obfuscation?",
     "Option 1": "To make files smaller in size",
     "Option 2": " To make files unreadable to unauthorized users",
     "Option 3": "To increase file access speed",
     "Option 4": "To organize files in a directory",
     "Correct answer": " To make files unreadable to unauthorized users"
    },
    {
     "Question No": 67,
     "Question": "Which of the following is NOT a common method used in file obfuscation?",
     "Option 1": " Encoding",
     "Option 2": " Encryption",
     "Option 3": "Compression",
     "Option 4": "Decryption",
     "Correct answer": "Decryption"
    },
    {
     "Question No": 68,
     "Question": "what is file obfuscation",
     "Option 1": "Encryption technique to secure files",
     "Option 2": " Technique to hide the real content and purpose of a file",
     "Option 3": "Compression method to reduce file size",
     "Option 4": "Method to rename files for organization",
     "Correct answer": " Technique to hide the real content and purpose of a file"
    },
    {
     "Question No": 69,
     "Question": "Which of the following is a type of malware specifically designed to spread rapidly across networks, often exploiting vulnerabilities in operating systems and software?",
     "Option 1": "Trojan horse",
     "Option 2": "Worm",
     "Option 3": "Spyware ",
     "Option 4": "Adware",
     "Correct answer": "Worm"
    },
    {
     "Question No": 70,
     "Question": "What type of malware disguises itself as legitimate software but carries out harmful actions once installed on a system?",
     "Option 1": "Adware ",
     "Option 2": "Spyware",
     "Option 3": "Trojan horse ",
     "Option 4": "Ransomware",
     "Correct answer": "Trojan horse"
    },
    {
     "Question No": 71,
     "Question": "What distinguishes a rootkit from other types of malware?",
     "Option 1": " It is primarily spread through email attachments.",
     "Option 2": "It modifies system functions to conceal its presence and activities.",
     "Option 3": "It encrypts files and demands payment for decryption.",
     "Option 4": "It displays intrusive advertisements on the user's screen.",
     "Correct answer": "It modifies system functions to conceal its presence and activities."
    },
    {
     "Question No": 72,
     "Question": "What term describes a type of malware that combines characteristics of viruses, worms, and trojan horses, often capable of propagating without human intervention?",
     "Option 1": " Ransomware",
     "Option 2": "Polymorphic malware",
     "Option 3": "Logic bomb",
     "Option 4": "Keylogger",
     "Correct answer": "Polymorphic malware"
    },
    {
     "Question No": 73,
     "Question": "what is the primary purpose of disassembling windows api functions",
     "Option 1": "to reverse engine malware",
     "Option 2": "to improve system performance",
     "Option 3": "to understand api functionality in detail",
     "Option 4": "all of the above",
     "Correct answer": "all of the above"
    },
    {
     "Question No": 74,
     "Question": " which of the following tool is not used for disassembling windows api functions",
     "Option 1": "debuggers",
     "Option 2": "disassemblers",
     "Option 3": "compilers ",
     "Option 4": "memory analyzers",
     "Correct answer": "compilers"
    },
    {
     "Question No": 75,
     "Question": "what is the major challenge assosiated with dissasembling windows api functions  ",
     "Option 1": "difficulty in understanding assembly language",
     "Option 2": "Potential for misinterpreting code due to compiler optimization",
     "Option 3": "limited access to relevant documentation",
     "Option 4": "all of the above",
     "Correct answer": "all of the above"
    },
    {
     "Question No": 76,
     "Question": "Which malware analysis technique relies on creating a signature or fingerprint of known malware to detect variants?",
     "Option 1": "Static analysis",
     "Option 2": "Dynamic analysis",
     "Option 4": "Heuristic analysis",
     "Correct answer": "Signature-based analysis"
    },
    {
     "Question No": 77,
     "Question": "Which of the following defensive measures do malware authors use to encode the original executable to protect it against static code analysis?",
     "Option 1": "Packing the malicious executable",
     "Option 2": "Employing fast-flux DNS techniques",
     "Option 3": "Targeting client-side vulnerabilities",
     "Option 4": "Embedding an imports table in the malicious executable",
     "Correct answer": "Packing the malicious executable"
    },
    {
     "Question No": 78,
     "Question": "What are the two most common phases of malware analysis?",
     "Option 1": "Behavioral and code analysis",
     "Option 2": "Registry and file system analysis",
     "Option 3": "User and kernel mode analysis",
     "Option 4": "Identification and containment analysis",
     "Correct answer": "Behavioral and code analysis"
    },
    {
     "Question No": 79,
     "Question": "Which of the following fields is NOT found in the Optional Header of a PE file",
     "Option 1": "ImageBase",
     "Option 2": "NumberOfSections",
     "Option 3": "AddressOfEntryPoint",
     "Option 4": "BaseOfCode",
     "Correct answer": "NumberOfSections"
    },
    {
     "Question No": 80,
     "Question": "Which field in the Optional Header specifies the size of the image, including all headers",
     "Option 1": "SizeOfHeaders",
     "Option 2": "SizeOfImage",
     "Option 3": "SizeOfCode",
     "Option 4": "SizeOfInitializedData",
     "Correct answer": "SizeOfImage"
    },
    {
     "Question No": 81,
     "Question": "Which field in the Optional Header specifies the preferred base address of the image when loaded into memory",
     "Option 1": "BaseOfData",
     "Option 2": "ImageBase",
     "Option 3": "EntryPoint",
     "Option 4": "BaseOfCode",
     "Correct answer": "ImageBase"
    },
    {
     "Question No": 82,
     "Question": "In a 64-bit PE file, which of the following is true regarding the IMAGE_OPTIONAL_HEADER?",
     "Option 1": "It contains 32-bit addresses.",
     "Option 2": "It includes a larger address space.",
     "Option 3": "It doesn't contain the AddressOfEntryPoint field.",
     "Option 4": "It has fewer fields compared to a 32-bit PE file.",
     "Correct answer": "It includes a larger address space.\n"
    },
    {
     "Question No": 83,
     "Question": ". What is the primary purpose of Process Hacker?",
     "Option 1": "Playing games",
     "Option 2": "Editing images",
     "Option 3": "Monitoring system resources, debugging software, and detecting malware",
     "Option 4": "Cooking recipes",
     "Correct answer": "c. Monitoring system resources, debugging software, and detecting malware"
    },
    {
     "Question No": 84,
     "Question": "What key combination is used to view detailed system performance information in Process Hacker?",
     "Option 1": "Ctrl+F",
     "Option 2": "Alt+Tab",
     "Option 3": "Ctrl+I",
     "Option 4": "Shift+Delete",
     "Correct answer": "c. Ctrl+I"
    },
    {
     "Question No": 85,
     "Question": "What feature in Process Hacker allows you to see active network connections and close them if necessary?",
     "Option 1": "a. Disk Activity",
     "Option 2": "b. Network Adapter Statistics",
     "Option 3": "c. GPU Usage",
     "Option 4": "d. System Performance Information",
     "Correct answer": "b. Network Adapter Statistics"
    },
    {
     "Question No": 86,
     "Question": "What can you do in Process Hacker if you need to close a handle associated with a file as a last resort?",
     "Option 1": ". Use Ctrl+F to search for the file",
     "Option 2": "b. Right-click on the file and select \"Close\"",
     "Option 3": "c. Press Alt+Tab",
     "Option 4": "d. Right-click an entry and close the handle associated with the file",
     "Correct answer": "d. Right-click an entry and close the handle associated with the file"
    },
    {
     "Question No": 87,
     "Question": "How does IDA Pro contribute to static analysis of native compiled applications?",
     "Option 1": "a:By debugging the application",
     "Option 2": "b:By providing a dynamic analysis environment",
     "Option 3": "c:By disassembling and analyzing binary code",
     "Option 4": "d:By compressing the injected code",
     "Correct answer": "c:By disassembling and analyzing binary code"
    },
    {
     "Question No": 88,
     "Question": "What is the maximum number of sections that can be defined in the PE header",
     "Option 1": 256,
     "Correct answer": 32768
    },
    {
     "Question No": 89,
     "Question": "Why is it recommended to pay close attention to the '.rsrc' section during runtime analysis?",
     "Option 1": "It contains the entry-point address",
     "Option 2": "It is usually large in malicious samples and can indicate dropper functionalities",
     "Option 3": "It lists imported function names",
     "Option 4": "It contains UI-related information",
     "Correct answer": "B) It is usually large in malicious samples and can indicate dropper functionalities",
     "Column8": "S SaiDath"
    },
    {
     "Question No": 90,
     "Question": "What does the 'Imports' section in PeStudio show?",
     "Option 1": "Exported functions",
     "Option 2": "Readable strings",
     "Option 3": " Imported function names",
     "Option 4": "TLS callback code",
     "Correct answer": "C) Imported function names",
     "Column8": "S SaiDath"
    },
    {
     "Question No": 91,
     "Question": "What does the 'TLS-callback' section contain?\n",
     "Option 1": " Code executed before the entry point, used for hiding malicious code",
     "Option 2": "Imported function names",
     "Option 3": "UI-related information",
     "Option 4": "MD5 hash and entropy of the file",
     "Correct answer": "A) Code executed before the entry point, used for hiding malicious code",
     "Column8": "S SaiDath"
    },
    {
     "Question No": 92,
     "Question": "What is the purpose of PeStudio",
     "Option 1": "To analyze network traffic",
     "Option 2": "To find suspicious artifacts within executable files",
     "Option 3": "To scan for vulnerabilities in web applications",
     "Option 4": "To manage software licenses",
     "Correct answer": "B. to find suspicious artifacts",
     "Column8": "S SaiDath"
    },
    {
     "Question No": 93,
     "Question": "What information can be obtained from Section Tab in PeStudio",
     "Option 1": "Import function names",
     "Option 2": "MD5 hash and entropy of the file",
     "Option 3": "Functions exported by the file",
     "Option 4": "TLS Callback mode",
     "Correct answer": "B. MD5 hash and entorpy of the file",
     "Column8": "S SaiDath"
    },
    {
     "Question No": 94
    },
    {
     "Question No": 95,
     "Question": "Which of the following Assembly language instructions is used for swapping the contents of two registers?",
     "Option 1": "MOV",
     "Option 2": "PUSH",
     "Option 3": "POP",
     "Option 4": "XCHG"
    },
    {
     "Question No": 96,
     "Question": "What does the MOV instruction in Assembly language primarily do?",
     "Option 1": "Add two operands",
     "Option 2": "Subtract two operands",
     "Option 3": "Move data from one location to another",
     "Option 4": "Perform bitwise AND operation"
    },
    {
     "Question No": 97,
     "Question": "Which advanced malware analysis technique involves reconstructing the malware's source code from its binary form?",
     "Option 1": "Code obfuscation",
     "Option 2": "Code emulation",
     "Option 3": "Code reverse engineering",
     "Option 4": "Code disassembly",
     "Correct answer": "Code reverse engineering"
    },
    {
     "Question No": 98,
     "Question": "Which of the following is a type of malware that disguises itself as legitimate software?",
     "Option 1": "Adware",
     "Option 2": "Ransomware",
     "Option 3": "Trojan",
     "Option 4": "worm",
     "Correct answer": "Trojan"
    },
    {
     "Question No": 99,
     "Question": "What type of malware encrypts files on a victim's computer and demands payment for decryption?",
     "Option 1": "Spyware",
     "Option 2": "Ransomware",
     "Option 3": "Adware",
     "Option 4": "worm",
     "Correct answer": "Ranswomware"
    },
    {
     "Question No": 100,
     "Question": "Which type of malware spreads through removable drives and network shares, often without user interaction?",
     "Option 1": "Spyware",
     "Option 2": "Worm",
     "Option 3": "Trojan",
     "Option 4": "Rootkit",
     "Correct answer": "Worm"
    },
    {
     "Question No": 101,
     "Question": "What type of malware is designed to steal sensitive information such as passwords or credit card numbers?",
     "Option 1": "Spyware",
     "Option 2": "Worm",
     "Option 3": "Trojan",
     "Option 4": "Rootkit",
     "Correct answer": "Spyware"
    },
    {
     "Question No": 102,
     "Question": "What is the primary purpose of a Trojan horse?",
     "Option 1": "Replicating itself",
     "Option 2": "Deleting files",
     "Option 3": "Gaining unauthorised access",
     "Option 4": "Slowing down computer perfromance",
     "Correct answer": "Gaining unauthorized access"
    },
    {
     "Question No": 103,
     "Question": "How does a rootkit typically operate?",
     "Option 1": "Infecting executable files",
     "Option 2": "Concealing its presence and providing unauthorized access",
     "Option 3": "Spreading through email attachments",
     "Option 4": "Deleting system files",
     "Correct answer": "Concealing its presence and providing unauthorized access"
    },
    {
     "Question No": 104,
     "Question": "What does the term sandboxing refer to?",
     "Option 1": "Creating a secure environment for testing and analyzing malware",
     "Option 2": "Hiding malware within the system",
     "Option 3": "Deleting infected files automatically",
     "Option 4": "Blocking internet access",
     "Correct answer": "Creating a secure environment for testing and analyzing malware"
    },
    {
     "Question No": 105,
     "Question": "What is the most common method of distributing malware?",
     "Option 1": "Social engineering",
     "Option 2": "Physical media",
     "Option 3": "Email attachments",
     "Option 4": "Website downloads",
     "Correct answer": "Email attachments"
    },
    {
     "Question No": 106,
     "Question": "What type of malware is designed to encrypt files and demand payment for their release?",
     "Option 1": "Ransomware",
     "Option 2": "Trojan",
     "Option 3": "Rootkit",
     "Option 4": "Worm",
     "Correct answer": "Ransomware"
    },
    {
     "Question No": 107,
     "Question": "which dll files exports functions related to service and registry?",
     "Option 1": "Kernal32.dll",
     "Option 2": "Gdi32.dll",
     "Option 3": "Advapi32.dll",
     "Option 4": "Urlmon.dll",
     "Correct answer": "Advapi32.dll"
    },
    {
     "Question No": 108,
     "Question": "which parameter specifies the action to take on the file which is creating a new file and opening an existing file?",
     "Option 1": "first ",
     "Option 2": "second",
     "Option 3": "fifth",
     "Option 4": "sixth",
     "Correct answer": "fifth"
    },
    {
     "Question No": 109,
     "Question": "What information can be obtained by disassembling a Windows API function?",
     "Option 1": "The function's purpose and functionality",
     "Option 2": "The specific registers used by the function",
     "Option 3": " The memory addresses accessed by the function",
     "Option 4": "All the above",
     "Correct answer": "All the above"
    },
    {
     "Question No": 110,
     "Question": "Disassembling Windows API functions can be helpful for which of the following purposes?",
     "Option 1": "Identifying security vulnerabilities",
     "Option 2": "Debugging software issues",
     "Option 3": " Understanding the behavior of malware",
     "Option 4": " All of the above",
     "Correct answer": "All the above"
    },
    {
     "Question No": 111
    },
    {
     "Question No": 112,
     "Question": "What does API hooking involve in the context of DLLs and malware analysis?",
     "Option 1": "Redirecting function calls to intercept and modify data or behavior",
     "Option 2": "Disabling antivirus software",
     "Option 3": "Encrypting API calls",
     "Option 4": "Bypassing firewalls",
     "Correct answer": "Redirecting function calls to intercept and modify data or behavior"
    },
    {
     "Question No": 113
    },
    {
     "Question No": 114,
     "Question": "In malware analysis, what is DLL sideloading commonly associated with?",
     "Option 1": "Exploiting vulnerabilities in the Windows operating system",
     "Option 2": "Evading antivirus detection",
     "Option 3": "Injecting malicious code into processes",
     "Option 4": "Bypassing firewalls",
     "Correct answer": "Evading antivirus detection"
    },
    {
     "Question No": 115,
     "Question": "Which dynamic analysis technique involves modifying a program to collect data about its runtime behavior?",
     "Option 3": "a) runtime monitoring"
    },
    {
     "Question No": 116,
     "Question": "Which Windows API function is commonly used to load a DLL into a process's address space?",
     "Option 1": " A) LoadLibrary ",
     "Option 3": "a) load library"
    },
    {
     "Question No": 117,
     "Question": "Execution Verifier is a dynamic tool that is also known as",
     "Option 1": "Test File Generator",
     "Option 2": "Coverage Analyzer",
     "Option 3": "Output Comparator",
     "Option 4": "Test Harness System",
     "Correct answer": "option 2"
    },
    {
     "Question No": 118,
     "Question": "Debugging Program is a program which runs concurrently with the program under test & provide commands to",
     "Option 1": "examine memory & registers",
     "Option 2": "stop execution at a particular point",
     "Option 3": "search for references for particular variables, constant and registers",
     "Option 4": "all of the mentioned",
     "Correct answer": "option 4"
    },
    {
     "Question No": 119,
     "Question": "Which of the following testing tools examine program systematically & automatically ?",
     "Option 1": "Code Inspector",
     "Option 2": "Static Analyzer",
     "Option 3": "Standard Enforcer",
     "Option 4": "Coverage Analyzer",
     "Correct answer": "option 2"
    },
    {
     "Question No": 120,
     "Question": "Which of the following techniques is NOT used in static code analysis?",
     "Option 1": "Data flow analysis",
     "Option 2": "Symbolic execution",
     "Option 3": "Code profiling",
     "Option 4": "Control flow analysis"
    },
    {
     "Question No": 121,
     "Question": "What is the primary disadvantage of relying solely on file extensions to determine file types?",
     "Option 1": "File extensions can be easily forged or manipulated.",
     "Option 2": "File extensions are not standardized across different operating systems.\n",
     "Option 3": " File extensions are typically encrypted, making them hard to read.",
     "Option 4": "File extensions do not provide sufficient information about the file's content.",
     "Correct answer": "File extensions can be easily forged or manipulated."
    },
    {
     "Question No": 122,
     "Question": "What term is commonly used to describe the process of analyzing file content to determine its type without executing it?",
     "Option 1": "Dynamic analysis",
     "Option 2": "Signature analysis",
     "Option 3": "Static analysis",
     "Option 4": "Behavioural analysis",
     "Correct answer": "Static analysis"
    },
    {
     "Question No": 123,
     "Question": "In static analysis, why is it important to verify both file extension and file header?",
     "Option 1": "File headers can be manipulated, so the extension provides a backup verification.",
     "Option 2": "File extensions are always reliable indicators of file type.",
     "Option 3": " File headers are prone to errors, so the extension serves as a fail-safe.",
     "Option 4": "Verifying both ensures redundancy in file type determination.",
     "Correct answer": "File headers can be manipulated, so the extension provides a backup verification."
    },
    {
     "Question No": 124,
     "Question": "Which of the following methods is commonly used to determine file type in static analysis?",
     "Option 1": "File extension\n",
     "Option 2": "File size\n",
     "Option 3": "File header or magic bytes",
     "Option 4": "File creation date\n\n",
     "Correct answer": "File header or magic bytes"
    },
    {
     "Question No": 125,
     "Question": "Which of the following tools best supports the concept of breakpoints?",
     "Option 1": "Debugger",
     "Option 2": "Disassembler",
     "Option 3": "sniffer ",
     "Option 4": "logger",
     "Correct answer": "debugger"
    },
    {
     "Question No": 126,
     "Question": "What are the two most common phases of malware analysis?",
     "Option 1": "Behavioral and code analysis",
     "Option 2": "identification and containment analysis",
     "Option 3": "Registry and file system analysis",
     "Option 4": "User and kernel mode analysis",
     "Correct answer": "Behavioral and code analysis"
    },
    {
     "Question No": 127,
     "Question": "Which of the following is not an hashing algorithm, used by malware?",
     "Option 1": "SHA-1",
     "Option 2": "SHA-2",
     "Option 3": "MD5",
     "Option 4": "None of these"
    },
    {
     "Question No": 128,
     "Question": "What is the primary purpose of extracting strings from a suspect bianry during malware analysis?",
     "Option 1": "To identify the programming language used",
     "Option 2": "To obtain information about the developer",
     "Option 3": "To reveal clues about the program functionality and potential indicators of malicious activity",
     "Option 4": "To decrypt sensitive information",
     "Column8": 12004478
    },
    {
     "Question No": 129,
     "Question": "How can string extraction aid in the identification of malware capabilities?",
     "Option 1": "By providing information about the malware's file size",
     "Option 2": "By revealing the malware's source code",
     "Option 3": "By containing references to attack commands, registry keys, and more",
     "Option 4": "By showing the malware's version number",
     "Column8": 12004478
    },
    {
     "Question No": 130,
     "Question": "Which of the following is not a visible register?",
     "Option 1": "General Purpose Registers",
     "Option 2": " Address Register",
     "Option 3": "Status Register",
     "Option 4": "MAR",
     "Correct answer": "MAR or the memory address register is not a visible register. This register is user inaccessible. It contains the address of the memory block to be read or written to.\n",
     "Column8": 12012740
    },
    {
     "Question No": 131,
     "Question": "CPU has built-in ability to execute a particular set of machine instructions, called as __________",
     "Option 1": "User instructions",
     "Option 2": "Sequence Set",
     "Option 3": "Registers",
     "Option 4": "Instruction Set\n",
     "Correct answer": "(d) An instruction is any task which is to be performed by the processor. Instructions are stored in the register. Instruction set is the set of machine instructions.",
     "Column8": 12012740
    },
    {
     "Question No": 132,
     "Question": "What is Purpose of Debugger?",
     "Option 1": "To write Code Faster",
     "Option 2": "To Find and Fix bugs in code",
     "Option 3": "To optimize code for perfomance",
     "Option 4": "To document code",
     "Correct answer": "b",
     "Column8": 12018685
    },
    {
     "Question No": 133,
     "Question": "In debugging, what does the term \"breakpoint\" refer to?",
     "Option 1": "A point where the code execution should stop for inspection",
     "Option 2": "A syntax error in code",
     "Option 3": "A point where code should resume execution",
     "Option 4": "A point where the  code crashes",
     "Correct answer": "c",
     "Column8": 12018685
    },
    {
     "Question No": 134,
     "Question": "which of the following tools is not  typically used for debugging binaries in Malware analysis",
     "Option 1": "GDB (GNU Debugger)",
     "Option 2": "IDA PRO (Interactive disassembler)",
     "Option 3": "OllyDbg(Windows Debugger)",
     "Option 4": "WireShark ",
     "Correct answer": "d",
     "Column8": 12018685
    },
    {
     "Question No": 135,
     "Question": "Which of the following statements accurately describes the purpose of debugging binaries?"
    },
    {
     "Question No": 136,
     "Question": "Which of the following tools is commonly used for disassembling Windows API functions?",
     "Option 1": "IDA Pro",
     "Option 2": "OllyDbg",
     "Option 3": "radare2",
     "Option 4": "Ghidra",
     "Correct answer": "IDA Pro",
     "Column8": 12011780
    },
    {
     "Question No": 137,
     "Question": "Which of the following is NOT a common disassembler used for analyzing Windows API functions?",
     "Option 1": "IDA Pro",
     "Option 2": " OllyDbg",
     "Option 3": "Ghidra",
     "Option 4": "DirectX Debugger (PIX)",
     "Correct answer": "DirectX Debugger (PIX)",
     "Column8": 12011780
    },
    {
     "Question No": 138,
     "Question": "Which of the following is a step commonly involved in disassembling Windows API functions using IDA Pro?",
     "Option 1": "Debugging the application using breakpoints",
     "Option 2": "Analyzing network traffic",
     "Option 3": "Reverse engineering the entire operating system",
     "Option 4": "Decompiling the source code into high-level languages",
     "Correct answer": "Debugging the application using breakpoints",
     "Column8": 12011780
    },
    {
     "Question No": 139,
     "Question": "What is the primary purpose of disassembling Windows API functions?",
     "Option 1": "To optimize the performance of Windows applications",
     "Option 2": "To reverse engineer and understand the behavior of Windows applications"
    },
    {
     "Question No": 140
    },
    {
     "Question No": 141,
     "Question": "Which of the following is not typically found in the PE header information?",
     "Option 1": "Import Table",
     "Option 2": "Export Table",
     "Option 3": "Resource Table",
     "Option 4": "Debugging Information",
     "Correct answer": "Debugging Information",
     "Column8": 12017261
    },
    {
     "Question No": 142,
     "Question": "What is the significance of the Import Table in the PE header?",
     "Option 1": "It lists all the exported functions from the executable.",
     "Option 2": "It specifies the libraries and functions that the executable imports.",
     "Option 3": "It contains information about the file's entry point.",
     "Option 4": "It stores information about the file's digital signature.",
     "Correct answer": "It specifies the libraries and functions that the executable imports.",
     "Column8": 12017261
    },
    {
     "Question No": 143,
     "Question": "Which field within the PE header provides information about the size of the code and data sections?",
     "Option 1": "SizeOfHeaders",
     "Option 2": "SizeOfCode",
     "Option 3": "SizeOfImage",
     "Option 4": "SizeOfInitializedData",
     "Correct answer": "SizeOfCode",
     "Column8": 12017261
    },
    {
     "Question No": 144,
     "Question": "Which technique is commonly used to monitor process during dynamic malware analysis ?",
     "Option 1": "Executing the Malware specimen",
     "Option 2": "Running the monitoring analysis tools",
     "Option 3": "Reverting to the clean snapshot",
     "Option 4": "None of the above",
     "Correct answer": "Option 4"
    },
    {
     "Question No": 145,
     "Question": "what is static analysis in context of data mining?",
     "Option 1": "analysing files while they are actively running",
     "Option 2": "analysing files without executing",
     "Option 3": "analysing files in real time",
     "Option 4": "analysing files through dynamic analysis only",
     "Correct answer": "Option 2"
    },
    {
     "Question No": 146,
     "Question": "what does procmon stand for ",
     "Option 1": "process monitor",
     "Option 2": "program monitor",
     "Option 3": "protocol monitor",
     "Option 4": "project monitor",
     "Correct answer": "Option 1"
    },
    {
     "Question No": 147,
     "Question": "which tab in procmon displays real time events as they occur",
     "Option 1": "process ",
     "Option 2": "file",
     "Option 3": "network",
     "Option 4": "event log",
     "Correct answer": "Option 4"
    },
    {
     "Question No": 148,
     "Question": "What term is used to describe malware that disguises itself as a regular program to trick users into installing it on their systems?",
     "Option 1": "Backdoor",
     "Option 2": "Adware",
     "Option 3": "Trojan",
     "Option 4": "Botnet",
     "Correct answer": "Trojan"
    },
    {
     "Question No": 149,
     "Question": "In malware classification, what distinguishes a worm from a virus?",
     "Option 1": "a) Worms need user intervention, while viruses can spread without user intervention.\n",
     "Option 2": "b) Viruses need user intervention, while worms can spread without user intervention.\n",
     "Option 3": "c) Both worms and viruses require user intervention to spread.\n",
     "Option 4": "d) Worms and viruses have identical spreading mechanisms.\n\n",
     "Correct answer": "Answer: b) Viruses need user intervention, while worms can spread without user intervention."
    },
    {
     "Question No": 150,
     "Question": "What is the term used to describe a group of computers infected with the same malware, waiting to receive instructions from a command-and-control server controlled by the attacker?\n\n",
     "Option 1": "Adware\n",
     "Option 2": "b) Botnet\n",
     "Option 3": "c) Ransomware\n",
     "Option 4": "d) Rootkit\n\n",
     "Correct answer": "Answer: b) Botnet"
    }]


export const questionsArr2 = [
    {
     "S.No": 1,
     "Question": "Instructions which won’t appear in the object program are called as _____",
     "Option 1": "Redundant instructions",
     "Option 2": "Exceptions",
     "Option 3": " Comments",
     "Option 4": "Assembler Directives",
     "Correct Answer": "Assembler Directives"
    },
    {
     "S.No": 2,
     "Question": "which of thw folllowing is a legitimate use of the DNA analysis technologiy",
     "Option 1": "Dynamic analysis",
     "Option 2": "Static analysis",
     "Option 3": "Heuristic analysis",
     "Option 4": " Behavioral analysis",
     "Correct Answer": "Dynamic analysis"
    },
    {
     "S.No": 3,
     "Question": "What is the primary purpose of dynamic malware analysis?",
     "Option 1": "To analyze malware behavior in a controlled environment",
     "Option 2": "To analyze malware source code for vulnerabilities",
     "Option 4": "To reverse engineer malware binaries to understand its functionality",
     "Correct Answer": "To analyze malware behavior in a controlled environment"
    },
    {
     "S.No": 4,
     "Question": "The purpose of the ORIGIN directive is __________",
     "Option 1": "Reserve",
     "Option 2": "Store",
     "Option 3": "Dataword",
     "Option 4": "EQU",
     "Correct Answer": "Dataword"
    },
    {
     "S.No": 5,
     "Question": "_____ directive is used to specify and assign the memory required for the block of code.",
     "Option 1": "Allocate",
     "Option 2": "assign",
     "Option 3": "set",
     "Option 4": "reserve",
     "Correct Answer": "reserve"
    },
    {
     "S.No": 6,
     "Question": "Which of the following is not typically displayed in a hex editor?",
     "Option 1": "Binary data",
     "Option 2": "Text data",
     "Option 3": "ASCII representation",
     "Option 4": "Decimal representation",
     "Correct Answer": "Decimal representation"
    },
    {
     "S.No": 7,
     "Question": "_____ directive specifies the end of execution of a program.",
     "Option 1": "end",
     "Option 2": "return",
     "Option 3": "stop",
     "Option 4": "terminate",
     "Correct Answer": "return"
    },
    {
     "S.No": 8,
     "Question": "Which of the following techniques is commonly used in static analysis to determine the file type of a given file?",
     "Option 1": "Dynamic execution",
     "Option 2": "File extension analysis",
     "Option 3": "Machine learning only",
     "Option 4": "None of the above",
     "Correct Answer": "File extension analysis"
    },
    {
     "S.No": 9,
     "Question": "Which operation is NOT commonly supported by hex editors?",
     "Option 1": "Find and replace",
     "Option 2": "Sorting",
     "Option 3": "Insertion and deletion of bytes",
     "Option 4": "Binary to decimal conversion",
     "Correct Answer": "sorting"
    },
    {
     "S.No": 11,
     "Question": "What is a common method used in dynamic analysis to monitor system activities during malware execution?",
     "Option 1": "Disassembling the malware code",
     "Option 2": "Running the malware in a virtual machine",
     "Option 3": "Analyzing network traffic patterns",
     "Option 4": "Employing intrusion detection systems",
     "Correct Answer": "Running the malware in a virtual machine"
    },
    {
     "S.No": 12,
     "Question": "which malware replicate itself without user intervention",
     "Option 1": "virus",
     "Option 2": "trojan horse",
     "Option 3": "spyware",
     "Option 4": "worm",
     "Correct Answer": "worm",
     "Column20": "abhinav"
    },
    {
     "S.No": 13,
     "Question": "which malware replicates itself with user intervention",
     "Option 1": "virus",
     "Option 2": "worm",
     "Option 3": "trojan ",
     "Option 4": "spyware",
     "Correct Answer": "virus",
     "Column20": "abhinav"
    },
    {
     "S.No": 14,
     "Question": "which malware gives the privileged access of victims' system",
     "Option 1": "ransomware",
     "Option 2": "rootkit",
     "Option 3": "spyware",
     "Option 4": "adware",
     "Correct Answer": "rootkit",
     "Column20": "abhinav"
    },
    {
     "S.No": 16,
     "Question": "What type of malware is designed to steal sensitive information, such as login credentials",
     "Option 1": "Trojan",
     "Option 2": "Worm",
     "Option 3": "Ransomware",
     "Option 4": "Adware",
     "Correct Answer": "Trojan."
    },
    {
     "S.No": 17,
     "Question": "When debugging malware, which of the following techniques can help in identifying its behavior and characteristics?",
     "Option 1": "Static analysis",
     "Option 2": "Dynamic analysis",
     "Option 3": "Reverse engineering",
     "Option 4": "All of the above",
     "Correct Answer": "All of the above"
    },
    {
     "S.No": 18,
     "Question": "What is Static Analysis?",
     "Option 1": "the analysis of",
     "Option 2": "the review of test",
     "Option 3": "the analysis of",
     "Option 4": "the use of black "
    },
    {
     "S.No": 20,
     "Question": "What is true regarding Static Analysis Tools?",
     "Option 1": "It compares actual and expected result.",
     "Option 2": "It gives quality information about code without executing it.",
     "Option 3": "It can detect memory leaks",
     "Option 4": "It tell about percentage of a code coverage.",
     "Correct Answer": "Ans:B"
    },
    {
     "S.No": 21,
     "Question": "Which of the following types of malware is specifically designed to encrypt files on a victim's system and demand payment for their decryption?",
     "Option 1": "Virus",
     "Option 2": "Worm",
     "Option 4": "Ransomware",
     "Correct Answer": "Ransomware"
    },
    {
     "S.No": 22,
     "Question": "Which malware type modifies or deletes files, disrupts system operations, and spreads to other systems?",
     "Option 1": "Virus",
     "Option 2": "Worm",
     "Option 3": "Trojan",
     "Option 4": "Ransomware",
     "Correct Answer": "vrius"
    },
    {
     "S.No": 23,
     "Question": "Which part of the PE header specifies the size of the image, including all headers, sections, and alignment padding?",
     "Option 1": "Size of Headers",
     "Option 2": "Size of Image",
     "Option 3": "Image Base",
     "Option 4": "Section Alignment",
     "Correct Answer": "Size of Image"
    },
    {
     "S.No": 24,
     "Question": "Which field in the PE header indicates the entry point of the executable code?",
     "Option 1": "Address of Entry Point",
     "Option 2": "Base of Code",
     "Option 3": "Address of Code",
     "Option 4": "Entry Point",
     "Correct Answer": "Entry Point"
    },
    {
     "S.No": 25,
     "Question": "Which component of the PE header determines the type of machine architecture for which the executable is intended?",
     "Option 1": "File Alignment",
     "Option 2": "Magic Number",
     "Option 3": "Machine",
     "Option 4": "Subsystem",
     "Correct Answer": "Machine"
    },
    {
     "S.No": 26,
     "Question": "What does the \"PE\" in PE header stand for?",
     "Option 1": "Portable Executable",
     "Option 2": "Program Entry",
     "Option 3": "Process Execution",
     "Option 4": "Primary Extension",
     "Correct Answer": "Portable Executable",
     "Column17": " "
    },
    {
     "S.No": 27,
     "Question": "Which of the following features is NOT typically found in PEStudio?",
     "Option 1": "Detection of common malware indicators",
     "Option 2": "Dynamic analysis of network traffic",
     "Option 3": " Identification of suspicious files",
     "Option 4": "Detection of hidden functions and code anomalies",
     "Correct Answer": "Dynamic analysis of network traffic"
    },
    {
     "S.No": 29,
     "Question": "Which tool is commonly used for disassembling Windows API functions?",
     "Option 1": " IDA Pro",
     "Option 2": " OllyDbg",
     "Option 3": " Wireshark",
     "Option 4": " Sublime Text",
     "Correct Answer": " IDA Pro"
    },
    {
     "S.No": 30,
     "Question": "Which language is often used for disassembling and analyzing Windows API calls?",
     "Option 1": "Python",
     "Option 2": " C++",
     "Option 3": " Assembly",
     "Option 4": " Java",
     "Correct Answer": " Assembly"
    },
    {
     "S.No": 31,
     "Question": "Which of the following is NOT a step in disassembling Windows API functions?",
     "Option 1": " Identifying API calls",
     "Option 2": " Analyzing network traffic",
     "Option 3": " Reverse engineering binary files",
     "Option 4": " Understanding function parameters",
     "Correct Answer": " Analyzing network traffic"
    },
    {
     "S.No": 32,
     "Question": "What is the purpose of disassembling Windows API functions?",
     "Option 1": " To develop new APIs",
     "Option 2": " To create software patches",
     "Option 3": " To understand how software interacts with the operating system",
     "Option 4": " To encrypt sensitive data",
     "Correct Answer": " To understand how software interacts with the operating system"
    },
    {
     "S.No": 33,
     "Question": "Which Windows API function is commonly used for file input\/output operations?",
     "Option 1": " GetProcAddress",
     "Option 2": " CreateFile",
     "Option 3": " LoadLibrary",
     "Option 4": " SendMessage",
     "Correct Answer": "CreateFile"
    },
    {
     "S.No": 35,
     "Question": "Which step of dynamic analysis involves identifying and removing defects from the software?",
     "Option 1": "Pepformance profiling",
     "Option 2": "Debugging",
     "Option 3": "Code coverage analysis",
     "Option 4": "Mutation testing",
     "Correct Answer": "Debugging"
    },
    {
     "S.No": 36,
     "Question": "Which step of dynamic analysis involves measuring various aspects of a program's performance, such as memory usage and execution time ?",
     "Option 1": "Instrumentation",
     "Option 2": "Performance profiling",
     "Option 3": "Debugging ",
     "Option 4": "Fuzz testing",
     "Correct Answer": "Performance profiling"
    },
    {
     "S.No": 37,
     "Question": "During dynamic analysis, what is the purpose of monitoring network activity?",
     "Option 1": "To identify the CPU usage of the malware",
     "Option 2": "To track the location of the malware author",
     "Option 3": "To observe communication with command and control servers"
    },
    {
     "S.No": 38,
     "Question": "What does \"PE\" stand for in the context of PE header in Windows executable files?",
     "Option 1": "A) Portable Executable"
    },
    {
     "S.No": 41,
     "Question": "Which of the following is NOT a challenge in fingerprinting malware?",
     "Option 1": " Evolving malware techniques",
     "Option 2": "Large signature databases",
     "Option 3": "Encryption of malware",
     "Option 4": " Rapid mutation of malware",
     "Correct Answer": "Large signature databases"
    },
    {
     "S.No": 42,
     "Question": "Which of the following is a common technique used in malware fingerprinting?",
     "Option 1": "Signature-based detection",
     "Option 2": " Random sampling",
     "Option 3": "Hardware analysis",
     "Option 4": "Social engineering",
     "Correct Answer": " Signature-based detection"
    },
    {
     "S.No": 43,
     "Question": "_______________________ is based on sniffer traces from the remote system.",
     "Option 1": "Active fingerprinting\n",
     "Option 2": "Passive fingerprinting",
     "Option 3": "OS fingerprinting",
     "Option 4": "Network fingerprinting",
     "Correct Answer": "Passive fingerprinting"
    },
    {
     "S.No": 44,
     "Question": "Which of the following do not comes under the important element of OS fingerprinting?",
     "Option 1": "TTL",
     "Option 2": "TOS",
     "Option 3": "DF bits",
     "Option 4": "Firewall",
     "Correct Answer": "Firewall"
    },
    {
     "S.No": 45,
     "Question": "Which of the following is NOT a widely used hex editor software?",
     "Option 1": "HxD",
     "Option 2": ") Hex Fiend",
     "Option 3": "Microsoft Word",
     "Option 4": "XVI32",
     "Correct Answer": "Microsoft word"
    },
    {
     "S.No": 46,
     "Question": "What is the purpose of file signature analysis in static analysis?",
     "Option 1": "To execute code within the file",
     "Option 2": "To identify unique byte sequences indicative of specific file types",
     "Option 3": "To analyze file permissions",
     "Option 4": "To determine file ownership",
     "Correct Answer": "To identify unique byte sequences indicative of specific file types"
    },
    {
     "S.No": 47,
     "Question": "What is the primary purpose of extracting strings during static analysis in malware analysis?",
     "Option 1": "Identifying the author of the malware",
     "Option 2": "Uncovering the encryption algorithm used",
     "Option 3": "Revealing hardcoded information and potential indicators of compromise",
     "Option 4": "Analyzing runtime behavior of the malware",
     "Correct Answer": "Revealing hardcoded information and potential indicators of compromise"
    },
    {
     "S.No": 48,
     "Question": "Which type of information can be revealed by analyzing strings in malware files?",
     "Option 1": "Temperature and environmental data",
     "Option 2": "Software version history",
     "Option 3": "Communication channels, such as URLs or IP addresses",
     "Option 4": "Physical location of the infected machine",
     "Correct Answer": "Communication channels, such as URLs or IP addresses"
    },
    {
     "S.No": 49,
     "Question": "Why is it important to look for API function calls in extracted strings during static analysis?",
     "Option 1": "To identify the programming language used in the malware",
     "Option 2": "To understand the malware's capabilities and potential behaviors",
     "Option 3": "To locate the malware's source code",
     "Option 4": "To determine the file size of the malware",
     "Correct Answer": "To understand the malware's capabilities and potential behaviors"
    },
    {
     "S.No": 50,
     "Question": "What role do encryption keys play in extracted strings, and how do they contribute to malware analysis?",
     "Option 1": "Encryption keys help identify the victim's personal information",
     "Option 2": "Encryption keys reveal the malware author's identity",
     "Option 3": "Encryption keys aid in understanding obfuscation and decryption routines",
     "Option 4": "Encryption keys are used to encrypt the entire filesystem",
     "Correct Answer": "Encryption keys aid in understanding obfuscation and decryption routines"
    },
    {
     "S.No": 53,
     "Question": "What does IDA stand for in the context of disassembly tools?",
     "Option 1": "Integrated Development Application",
     "Option 2": "Interactive Disassembler",
     "Option 3": "Instructional Debugging Analyzer",
     "Option 4": "Intelligent Data Aggregator",
     "Correct Answer": "OPTION B"
    },
    {
     "S.No": 54,
     "Question": "Which of the following file formats is commonly used with IDA for analyzing binary executables?",
     "Option 1": ".txt",
     "Option 2": ".pdf",
     "Option 3": ".exe",
     "Option 4": ".zip",
     "Correct Answer": "OPTION C"
    },
    {
     "S.No": 55,
     "Question": "What is the primary purpose of IDA's graph view in disassembly analysis?",
     "Option 1": "To display images and icons.",
     "Option 2": "To show a visual representation of program control flow.",
     "Option 3": "To organize functions alphabetically.",
     "Option 4": "To list hexadecimal values of instructions.",
     "Correct Answer": "OPTION B"
    },
    {
     "S.No": 56,
     "Question": "Which programming languages are commonly associated with IDA's disassembly analysis?",
     "Option 1": "Java and Python",
     "Option 2": "C and C++",
     "Option 3": "HTML and CSS",
     "Option 4": "Ruby and PHP",
     "Correct Answer": "OPTION B"
    },
    {
     "S.No": 57,
     "Question": "What information can be obtained through malware fingerprinting?",
     "Option 1": "Physical location of the malware creator",
     "Option 2": "Type and variant of malware",
     "Option 3": "Favorite color of the malware author",
     "Option 4": "Weather conditions at the time of malware creation",
     "Correct Answer": "Type and variant of malware"
    },
    {
     "S.No": 58,
     "Question": "Which technique involves creating a signature to detect specific malware patterns?",
     "Option 1": "DNA analysis",
     "Option 2": "Fingerprinting",
     "Option 3": "Handwriting recognition",
     "Option 4": "Facial recognition",
     "Correct Answer": "Fingerprinting"
    },
    {
     "S.No": 60,
     "Question": "Which of the following techniques examines the internal structure of a file to determine its type?",
     "Option 1": "Pattern matching",
     "Option 2": "File extension analysis",
     "Option 3": "Header analysis",
     "Option 4": "File content analysis",
     "Correct Answer": "Header analysis"
    },
    {
     "S.No": 62,
     "Question": "……………… techniques rely on the manual examination and automated analysis of the code or other project documentation without the execution of the code.",
     "Option 1": "Static testing",
     "Option 2": "Dynamic testing",
     "Option 3": "Reviews",
     "Option 4": "All",
     "Correct Answer": "Static testing"
    },
    {
     "S.No": 64,
     "Question": "What is the distinguishing characteristic of a logic bomb?",
     "Option 1": "To enhance the aesthetic appearance of malicious code",
     "Option 2": "To detect and identify specific characteristics or attributes of malware",
     "Option 3": "To create unique digital signatures for legitimate software",
     "Option 4": "To improve the performance of antivirus software",
     "Correct Answer": "To detect and identify specific characteristics or attributes of malware\n"
    },
    {
     "S.No": 65,
     "Question": "Which technique is commonly used for fingerprinting malware based on unique characteristics?\n\n",
     "Option 1": "MAC Address analysis",
     "Option 2": "Signature-based detection",
     "Option 3": " IP Address tracking",
     "Option 4": "Port Scanning",
     "Correct Answer": "Signature-based detection"
    },
    {
     "S.No": 66,
     "Question": "Which of the following is a legitimate use of DNA analysis technology?",
     "Option 1": "Detecting genetic diseases",
     "Option 2": "Creating computer viruses",
     "Option 3": "Hacking into computer systems",
     "Option 4": "Improving internet speed",
     "Correct Answer": "Detecting genetic diseases"
    },
    {
     "S.No": 67,
     "Question": "Which of the following is NOT a common method used by malware to infect a system?",
     "Option 1": "Email attachments",
     "Option 2": "Drive-by downloads",
     "Option 3": "Physical contact with infected devices",
     "Option 4": "Social engineering",
     "Correct Answer": "Physical contact with infected devices"
    },
    {
     "S.No": 68,
     "Question": " What is the primary purpose of using sandboxes when debugging malware?",
     "Option 1": " a) To analyze the malware's network communication",
     "Option 2": " To provide a realistic environment for the malware to execute.",
     "Option 3": "To isolate the malware and prevent it from harming the system..",
     "Option 4": "  To modify the malware's code and observe the changes.",
     "Correct Answer": " To isolate the malware and prevent it from harming the system."
    },
    {
     "S.No": 69,
     "Question": " What is a potential risk associated with debugging malware?",
     "Option 1": ".a) It may damage the system hardware.",
     "Option 2": "It may corrupt other files on the system.",
     "Option 3": "The malware may escape the sandbox and infect the system.",
     "Option 4": "It requires extensive programming knowledge.",
     "Correct Answer": "The malware may escape the sandbox and infect the system"
    },
    {
     "S.No": 70,
     "Question": "When debugging malware, it is crucial to:",
     "Option 1": "Run the malware directly on the main system.",
     "Option 2": "prioritize speed and efficiency over thorough analysis.",
     "Option 3": "Document all observations and findings meticulously.",
     "Option 4": "Trust the information displayed by the malware itself.",
     "Correct Answer": "Document all observations and findings meticulously.."
    },
    {
     "S.No": 71,
     "Question": "What is the purpose of reverse engineering in malware analysis?"
    },
    {
     "S.No": 73,
     "Question": "Which tool is commonly used for disassembling Windows API functions and analyzing their assembly code?"
    },
    {
     "S.No": 74,
     "Option 1": "IDA PRO",
     "Option 2": "Visual Studio Code",
     "Option 3": "Notepad++",
     "Option 4": "Sublime Test",
     "Correct Answer": "IDA Pro"
    },
    {
     "S.No": 75,
     "Question": "What is the significance of the IDA Pro tool in the context of disassembling Windows API?",
     "Option 1": "Debugging applications",
     "Option 2": "Enhancing software performance",
     "Option 3": "Understanding malware behavior",
     "Option 4": "Improving user interface design",
     "Correct Answer": "Understanding Malware behaviour"
    },
    {
     "S.No": 76,
     "Question": "Which of the following registers is commonly used to pass parameters to Windows API functions in x86 assembly code?",
     "Option 1": "EAX",
     "Option 2": "EDX",
     "Option 3": "ECX",
     "Option 4": "All of the above",
     "Correct Answer": "All of the above"
    },
    {
     "S.No": 77,
     "Question": "What is the primary purpose of disassembling Windows API calls ?",
     "Option 1": "Graphics rendering",
     "Option 2": "Debugging and analyzing memory dumps",
     "Option 3": "Code compilation",
     "Option 4": "GUI design for Windows applications",
     "Correct Answer": "Debugging and analyzing memory dumps"
    },
    {
     "S.No": 78,
     "Question": "What does the \"PE\" in PE header stand for?"
    },
    {
     "S.No": 79,
     "Question": "3. P-hacking can be detrimental to research because it:",
     "Option 1": "(a) Requires advanced hacking skills.",
     "Option 2": "(b) May lead to inaccurate and misleading scientific conclusions. (Correct)",
     "Option 3": "(c) Always involves illegal activities.",
     "Option 4": "(d) Is a common practice in all scientific fields.",
     "Correct Answer": "(b) May lead to inaccurate and misleading scientific conclusions. (Correct)"
    },
    {
     "S.No": 81,
     "Question": "which one is the right purpose of wireshark",
     "Option 1": "video editing",
     "Option 2": "packet sniffing",
     "Option 3": "web devlopment",
     "Option 4": "code compilation",
     "Correct Answer": "Packet sniffing"
    },
    {
     "Question": "At which layer wireshark works",
     "Option 1": "Application layer",
     "Option 2": "network layer",
     "Option 3": "data link layer",
     "Option 4": "Both B and C",
     "Correct Answer": "Both B and C"
    },
    {
     "Question": "which one is not the purpose of wireshark",
     "Option 1": "packet sniffing",
     "Option 2": "packet analysis",
     "Option 3": "packet injection",
     "Option 4": "protocol decryption",
     "Correct Answer": "packet injection"
    },
    {
     "S.No": 82,
     "Question": "wireshark is ___________source software",
     "Option 1": "open source",
     "Option 2": "only available for MNCs",
     "Option 3": "Both A and B",
     "Option 4": "None of the above",
     "Correct Answer": "packet sniffing"
    },
    {
     "S.No": 83
    },
    {
     "S.No": 84,
     "Question": "Which of the following is a common use of a hex editor?",
     "Option 1": "Editing source code",
     "Option 2": "Modifying system settings",
     "Option 3": "Analyzing and editing binary data",
     "Option 4": "Creating graphical interfaces",
     "Correct Answer": "editing source code"
    },
    {
     "S.No": 85,
     "Question": "P hacking is a practice of",
     "Option 1": "intentional manipulating  data to get a desired statistical outcome",
     "Option 2": "writing secure code to prevent hacking attempts",
     "Option 3": "identifying and patching vulnerabilities in software systems",
     "Option 4": "using social engineering techniques to gain authorized access to information",
     "Correct Answer": "manipulating data or analysis method to obtain desired outcome"
    },
    {
     "S.No": 86,
     "Question": "2. Which of the following is NOT a common P-hacking technique?",
     "Option 1": "(a) Collecting data until a statistically significant result is achieved. (Incorrect) - This is a common technique, but not considered ethical.",
     "Option 2": "(b) Excluding data points that do not support the desired outcome.",
     "Option 3": "(c) Failing to disclose relevant limitations of the research methodology.",
     "Option 4": "(d) Replicating the study with different methods or datasets.",
     "Correct Answer": "(a) Collecting data until a statistically significant result is achieved. (Incorrect) - This is a common technique, but not considered ethical."
    },
    {
     "S.No": 88,
     "Question": "The operations performed by data transfer instructions are on",
     "Option 1": "bit data",
     "Option 2": "byte data",
     "Option 3": "16-bit data",
     "Option 4": "all of the mentioned",
     "Correct Answer": "all of the mentioned"
    },
    {
     "S.No": 89,
     "Question": "The data address of look-up table is found by adding the contents of",
     "Option 1": "register instructions",
     "Option 2": "register specific instructions",
     "Option 3": "direct addressing",
     "Option 4": "immediate mode",
     "Correct Answer": "immediate mode"
    },
    {
     "S.No": 90,
     "Question": "\t\nThe data address of look-up table is found by adding the contents of",
     "Option 1": "accumulator with that of program counter",
     "Option 2": "accumulator with that of program counter or data pointer",
     "Option 3": "data register with that of program counter or accumulator",
     "Option 4": "data register with that of program counter or data pointer",
     "Correct Answer": "accumulator with that of program counter or data pointer"
    },
    {
     "S.No": 91,
     "Question": "when we add two numbers the destination adderess must always be",
     "Option 1": "some immediate data",
     "Option 2": "any register",
     "Option 3": "accumulator",
     "Option 4": "memory",
     "Correct Answer": "accumulator"
    },
    {
     "S.No": 92,
     "Question": "Which of the following is the FIRST step in dynamic analysis of malware?",
     "Option 1": "Executing the malware in a controlled sandbox environment.",
     "Option 2": "Reversing the malware's code using a disassembler.",
     "Option 3": "Identifying suspicious strings or resources within the malware.",
     "Option 4": " Patching the system vulnerabilities that the malware might exploit.",
     "Correct Answer": " Executing the malware in a controlled sandbox environment."
    },
    {
     "S.No": 93,
     "Question": "What is the primary goal of analyzing malware?",
     "Option 1": "To understand its technical capabilities and potential impact.",
     "Option 2": "To develop a signature for antivirus software to detect similar threats.",
     "Option 3": "To reverse engineer the malware and create a countermeasure.",
     "Option 4": " All of the above.",
     "Correct Answer": " All of the above."
    },
    {
     "S.No": 94,
     "Question": "What is a disadvantage of using a sandbox environment for DLL analysis?",
     "Option 1": "Sandboxes might not accurately replicate the real-world environment and interactions.",
     "Option 2": " DLLs might not function correctly due to limited resources in the sandbox.",
     "Option 3": "Sandboxes cannot be used to analyze network activity associated with the DLL.",
     "Option 4": "All of the above.",
     "Correct Answer": "All of the above."
    },
    {
     "S.No": 95,
     "Question": "Which of the following statements is NOT true about using IDA for static code analysis?",
     "Option 1": "IDA allows you to disassemble machine code into assembly language for manual inspection.",
     "Option 2": "You can use IDA's built-in functions to identify potential malware characteristics like suspicious API calls.",
     "Option 3": "Static analysis in IDA requires running the malware, making it a dynamic analysis technique.",
     "Option 4": "IDA can be used to analyze different processor architectures by selecting the appropriate instruction set.",
     "Correct Answer": "Static analysis in IDA requires running the malware, making it a dynamic analysis technique."
    },
    {
     "S.No": 96,
     "Question": "When performing static analysis in IDA, what information can be gleaned from function names and comments?",
     "Option 1": "The intended functionality of the code segment.",
     "Option 2": "The specific instructions used to implement the functionality.",
     "Option 3": "Whether the code is malicious or benign based solely on naming conventions.",
     "Option 4": "All of the above.",
     "Correct Answer": "All of the above."
    },
    {
     "S.No": 97,
     "Question": "What is the advantage of using IDA's graphing capabilities during static analysis?",
     "Option 1": "It allows for visualization of the overall program flow and potential control flow hijacking attempts.",
     "Option 2": " It enables the identification of unused code sections, which might indicate obfuscation techniques.",
     "Option 3": "It helps differentiate between legitimate and malicious code based on visual patterns",
     "Option 4": "Both (a) and (b).",
     "Correct Answer": "Both (a) and (b)."
    },
    {
     "S.No": 98,
     "Question": "How can IDA's built-in debugger be helpful during static analysis, even though it's not technically dynamic analysis?",
     "Option 1": "It allows for limited execution of specific code sections to observe their behavior within a controlled environment.",
     "Option 2": "It provides additional information about register values and memory usage, aiding in understanding code logic.",
     "Option 3": " It enables setting breakpoints to analyze specific points in the code's execution (not possible in static analysis",
     "Option 4": "Both (a) and (b).",
     "Correct Answer": "Both (a) and (b)."
    },
    {
     "S.No": 101,
     "Question": "Which of the following is NOT a feature of PE Studio's user interface?"
    },
    {
     "S.No": 102,
     "Question": "Which programming language is PE Studio primarily written in?",
     "Option 1": "Hexadecimal Viewer",
     "Option 2": "Dependency graph",
     "Option 3": "Debugger",
     "Option 4": "Disassembler",
     "Correct Answer": "Debugger"
    },
    {
     "S.No": 103,
     "Question": "Which section of PE files does PE Studio primarily analyze?",
     "Option 1": "java",
     "Option 2": "python",
     "Option 3": "c++",
     "Option 4": "Ruby",
     "Correct Answer": "Python"
    },
    {
     "S.No": 104,
     "Question": "What is the output format of PE Studio analysis?",
     "Option 1": "Header",
     "Option 2": "data",
     "Option 3": "footer ",
     "Option 4": "Metadata",
     "Correct Answer": "Header"
    },
    {
     "S.No": 106,
     "Question": "What file extension is used for ProcMon log files?"
    },
    {
     "S.No": 107,
     "Question": "ProcMon can capture events related to which of the following activities?",
     "Option 1": ".log",
     "Option 2": ".pml",
     "Option 3": ".procmon",
     "Option 4": ".pmlog",
     "Correct Answer": ".pml"
    },
    {
     "S.No": 108,
     "Question": "What is the default refresh rate for ProcMon?",
     "Option 1": "File creation ",
     "Option 2": "reistry modifiction",
     "Option 3": "Network packet trans mission ",
     "Option 4": "All of the above",
     "Correct Answer": "All of the above"
    },
    {
     "S.No": 109,
     "Question": "Which of the following can be used to filter events in ProcMon?",
     "Option 1": "1 sec",
     "Option 2": " 5 sec",
     "Option 3": "10 sec",
     "Option 4": "30 sec",
     "Correct Answer": "10 sec"
    },
    {
     "S.No": 110,
     "Question": "What is the maximum number of filters that can be applied in ProcMon?",
     "Option 1": "Process name ",
     "Option 2": "PID",
     "Option 3": "Operation",
     "Option 4": "All of the above",
     "Correct Answer": "All of the above"
    },
    {
     "S.No": 112,
     "Question": "What is a better alternative to p-hacking when analyzing data?",
     "Option 2": "b) Predetermining the desired outcome and manipulating data to achieve that result.",
     "Option 3": "c) Clearly pre-registering your research hypothesis, methodology, and analysis plan before collecting data.",
     "Option 4": "Focusing solely on the statistical significance of results, regardless of the practical implications.",
     "Correct Answer": "Clearly pre-registering your research hypothesis, methodology, and analysis plan before collecting data."
    },
    {
     "S.No": 115,
     "Question": "What is a limitation of using static analysis for file type determination?",
     "Option 1": "It requires specialized software and expertise.",
     "Option 3": "It is only applicable to binary files, not text files.",
     "Option 4": "All of the above are limitations",
     "Correct Answer": "It may not be able to identify all file types accurately"
    },
    {
     "S.No": 118,
     "Question": "In debugging, what does the term \"stack trace\" refer to?"
    },
    {
     "S.No": 120,
     "Question": "What does the term \"rubber duck debugging\" refer to?",
     "Option 1": "A) Debugging with a rubber duck as a companion",
     "Option 2": "B) Debugging underwater code",
     "Option 3": "C) Debugging without using tools",
     "Option 4": "D) Debugging with rubber gloves on"
    },
    {
     "S.No": 127,
     "Question": "What is the purpose of a watchpoint in debugging?",
     "Option 1": "A) To watch the program's output",
     "Option 2": "B) To monitor code execution speed",
     "Option 3": "C) To break the program",
     "Option 4": "D) To track changes in a variable"
    },
    {
     "S.No": 129,
     "Question": "How can researchers prevent P-hacking in their work?",
     "Option 1": "Avoiding pre-registration of research plans.",
     "Option 2": "Pre-registering research methods and hypotheses before data collection",
     "Option 3": "Focusing solely on positive results and ignoring negative findings.",
     "Option 4": "Not sharing their research data with other scientists.",
     "Correct Answer": "Pre-registering research methods and hypotheses before data collection."
    },
    {
     "S.No": 131,
     "Question": "What is PEStudio primarily used for?",
     "Option 1": "Network monitoring",
     "Option 2": "Malware analysis",
     "Option 3": "Web development",
     "Option 4": "Data visualization",
     "Correct Answer": "Malware analysis"
    },
    {
     "S.No": 132,
     "Question": "What does PE stand for in PEStudio?",
     "Option 1": "Personal Edition",
     "Option 2": "Private Environment",
     "Option 3": "Portable Executable",
     "Option 4": "Program Environment",
     "Correct Answer": "Portable Executable"
    },
    {
     "S.No": 133,
     "Question": "Which of the following best describes PEStudio?",
     "Option 1": "A video editing software",
     "Option 2": "A static analysis tool for Windows executable files",
     "Option 3": "A social media management tool",
     "Option 4": "An antivirus program",
     "Correct Answer": "A static analysis tool for Windows executable files"
    },
    {
     "S.No": 136,
     "Question": "which drive is used to capture packets when wireshark is running on a apple computer?",
     "Option 1": "macpcap",
     "Option 2": "airpcap",
     "Option 3": "libpcap"
    },
    {
     "S.No": 138,
     "Question": "What is the term used for manipulating research methods to ensure a statistically significant result?",
     "Option 1": "(a) Data mining",
     "Option 2": "P-hacking",
     "Option 3": "(c) Hypothesis testing",
     "Option 4": "(d) Replication",
     "Correct Answer": "P hacking"
    },
    {
     "S.No": 140,
     "Question": "Which of the following main activities are performed in the planning phase of a formal review?",
     "Option 1": "i, ii and iii only",
     "Option 2": "i, ii and iv only",
     "Option 3": "ii, iii and iv only",
     "Option 4": "All i, ii, iii and iv",
     "Correct Answer": "i, ii and iv only"
    },
    {
     "S.No": 142,
     "Question": "a key logger is an example of",
     "Option 1": "spyware",
     "Option 2": "trojan",
     "Option 3": "worm",
     "Option 4": "logic boom",
     "Correct Answer": "spyware"
    },
    {
     "S.No": 143,
     "Question": "Which of the following describes the main phases of a formal review?",
     "Option 1": "A) Initiation, backtracking, individual preparation, review meeting, rework, follow-up",
     "Option 2": "B) Planning, individual preparation, review meeting, rework, closure, follow-up",
     "Option 3": "C) Planning, kick-off, individual preparation, review meeting, rework, follow-up",
     "Option 4": "D) Individual preparation, review meeting, rework, closure, follow-up, root cause analysis",
     "Correct Answer": "Planning, kick-off, individual preparation, review meeting, rework, follow-up"
    },
    {
     "S.No": 146,
     "Question": "Which of the following is a common debugging technique?",
     "Option 1": "A) Adding more features",
     "Option 2": "B) Removing all code",
     "Option 3": "C) Printing variables and values",
     "Option 4": "D) Ignoring errors"
    },
    {
     "S.No": 147,
     "Question": "What does \"PE\" stand for in the context of PE header in Windows executable files?"
    },
    {
     "S.No": 150,
     "Question": "type in the name of the pcap driver used when running wireshark on a windows computer ?",
     "Option 1": "winpcap"
    },
    {
     "S.No": 152,
     "Question": "What is Wireshark primarily used for in the context of malware analysis?",
     "Option 1": "a) Executing malware samples",
     "Option 2": "b) Analyzing network traffic",
     "Option 3": "c) Debugging malware code"
    },
    {
     "S.No": 153,
     "Question": "Which feature of Wireshark is helpful in identifying malicious network traffic?",
     "Option 1": "a) Packet capture",
     "Option 2": "b) Protocol dissection",
     "Option 3": "c) Traffic filtering"
    },
    {
     "S.No": 154,
     "Question": "Which of the following protocols might be used by malware and can be analyzed using Wireshark?",
     "Option 1": "a) HTTP",
     "Option 2": "b) FTP"
    },
    {
     "S.No": 155,
     "Question": "Wireshark can capture traffic on which types of networks?",
     "Option 1": "a) Wired only",
     "Option 2": "b) Wireless only"
    },
    {
     "S.No": 157,
     "Question": "What is the distinguishing characteristic of a logic bomb?",
     "Option 1": "It spreads rapidly across networks.",
     "Option 2": "It encrypts files and demands payment.",
     "Option 3": "t triggers a malicious action at a specific time or event.",
     "Option 4": "It displays unwanted advertisements.",
     "Correct Answer": "It triggers a malicious action at a specific time or event."
    },
    {
     "S.No": 160,
     "Question": "Which of the following activities does not include within follow-up phase of formal review?",
     "Option 1": "Checking that defects have been addressed",
     "Option 2": "Gathering metrics",
     "Option 3": "Fixing defects found",
     "Option 4": "Checking on exit criteria",
     "Correct Answer": "Fixing defects found"
    },
    {
     "S.No": 162,
     "Question": "What is the role of peer review in preventing p-hacking?",
     "Option 1": "(a) Peer reviewers are not trained to identify p-hacking techniques",
     "Option 2": "(b) Careful peer review can help identify and flag suspicious practices (Answer)",
     "Option 3": "(c) Peer review ensures the quality of writing, not the methods used",
     "Option 4": "(d) Peer review is not effective in preventing misconduct",
     "Correct Answer": "(b) Careful peer review can help identify and flag suspicious practices (Answer)"
    },
   
   ]